Let's
conclude
our
story
by
revealing
the
true
identity
of
Araragi
Tsukihi.
Let's conclude our story by revealing
阿良々木月火の正体を開示することによって
それではいよいよ 僕達の物語に終止符を打つことにしよう
the true identity of Araragi Tsukihi.
お兄ちゃんはいつもそう
You're always like that, Onii-chan.
私と火憐ちゃんのことを子供扱いばっかりして
You always treat us like children.
The
story
of
smaller
little
sister
my
bratty
and
annoying
these
episodes
will bring
of my
beloved
companions
and me
to a
close.
The story of my bratty and annoying
あの小賢しくも小うるさい ちっちゃい方の妹の話で
smaller little sister will bring these episodes
僕と僕の愛すべき仲間達のエピソードは完結だ
of my beloved companions and me to a close.
How come you don't know?
何で知らないのよ
I'm platinum mad!
プラチナむかつく
Araragi
Tsukihi.
One of
the Fire
Sisters.
The
younger
little
sister.
The
smaller
little
sister.
Second
year in
middle
school.
Born
in
April.
years old.
Blood
type
B.
A
h
y
s
t
e
r
i
c
Araragi Tsukihi.
阿良々木月火 ファイヤーシスターズの片割れ
One of the Fire Sisters.
The younger little sister.
下の妹 ちっちゃい方の妹
The smaller little sister.
Second year in middle school.
中学二年生で四月生まれで 14歳でB型で
Born in April.
14 years old.
Blood type B.
ヒステリックで
A hysteric.
お兄ちゃんに言われたくありません
I don't want to hear that from you.
S
l
y
Sly.
ずる賢く
You can be mad at Karen-chan,
火憐ちゃんは怒ってもいいけど 私のことは怒らないで
but please don't get mad at me.
Impulsive and easily agitated.
Impulsive
and
easily
agitated.
感情がピーキーで
Huh?
あれお兄ちゃん さっきの子は
Onii-chan, where's that girl?
And
ortal.
imm
This
is the
story
of just
another
fake.
そして不死身な ただの偽物の物語だ
And immortal.
This is the story of just another fake.
It seems necessary to stress the fact
that my relationship with my sisters is not particularly tight.
If you take the relationship between my younger sisters, Tsukihi, and Karen,
they really are close, probably since they were born within a year of each other.
But unfortunately, I can't say I'm as close to them as they are to each other.
It'd be more appropriate to say that we're on bad terms,
or maybe, I could even go as far as to use the word "dislike".
Karen and Tsukihi, on one end, are both constantly rebelling against me,
and I, on the other end, get fed up with their insolent ideas.
I especially can't tolerate
their justice games, calling themselves the Fire Sisters.
It seems as though the Kaiki Deishuu incident
wasn't enough to change that.
Tsukihi Phoenix Part 1
Episode 8
Type Font Used HGP Minchou B
Pray for success in academics
August 14th
Monday Morning
Animation Number 21
Sole
兄ちゃん 何かあたしにしてほしいことないかな
Nii-chan, would you like me to do anything?
Sole
No.
ねえよ
ええ なんかあるだろ
Surely there's something, right?
ねー兄ちゃん 何か兄ちゃんの役に立ちたいんだよ
Come on, Nii-chan...
I want to be useful to you.
あたしはこう見えて 頼りになる妹なんだぜ
I may not look it, but I'm a very helpful little sister...
尽くす妹なんだぜ ご奉仕しちゃう妹なんだぜ
A dedicated little sister...
A little sister ready to serve you!
Nothing...
ねえよ だからねえよ
There's nothing!
Nothing I would want my little sister to do so early in the morning!
こんな朝っぱらから 妹にしてほしいことなんざあるわけねえだろ
There's nothing I want you to do for me,
僕にして欲しいことはないし そしてお前にできることもない
and there's nothing you can do...
PRACTICE
DRILLS
XX Bookstore
As you can see, I'm trying to concentrate on studying.
見ての通り僕は今集中して勉強してんだからよ
C
English
Drills
5 P0INT
With 500 words that are easily memorized
C
Like reading manga!
Fun translations!
Cute illustrations
EASY
with footnotes that will help
your memory
Memorizing everyday words
will become natural to you!
Leave it to me
I don't have time to play with a lower life form like you,
お前如き下等生物と遊んでなんかられねーんだ
you single-celled organism!
この単細胞が
暇なんだったらその辺走ってこいよ
If you're bored, go run through the fields.
You don't have to come back...
別に帰ってこなくていいから...
Um...
えっと
Araragi Karen, my little sister, is wearing a skirt.
阿良々木火憐 僕の妹がスカートを穿いていた
Who is this pretty girl?
誰だこの綺麗系女子
火憐ちゃん お前いじめられてるんだったら先ず僕に言えよ
Karen-chan!
If someone's bullying you, tell me!
Why didn't you talk to me
そんな酷いことになる前に どうして相談してくれなかったんだ
before this awful thing happened?
いや いじめられてねえよ
No, nobody's bullying me.
If anyone is, it's you, Nii-chan.
強いて言うなら あたしをいじめるのは兄ちゃんだ
今だから笑って言えるけど あたし小学生の頃
I can laugh about this now.
But during elementary school,
兄ちゃんから受けた心ない言葉で自殺を考えたことあるからな
some of your thoughtless words nearly drove me to suicide.
That was when I started trying to become an ally of justice.
その辺がきっかけであたしは正義の味方を志したんだ
あたしの中の悪を憎む心は 兄ちゃんが生み出したのさ
You created this hatred for evil in my heart.
But... But, Karen-chan...
いや だけど...だけど火憐ちゃん 誰かに脅されなきゃ
If no one's threatening you,
there's no way you would dress like this!
お前がそんな格好をするわけないじゃないか
安心しろ火憐ちゃん 僕が何とかしてやる
Don't worry, Karen-chan.
I'll do something.
Leave it all to your big brother.
あとのことは全てこの兄に任せておけ
Let's start with you giving me
さしあたってはお前をいじめた奴の住所と携帯番号
the addresses and cell phone
numbers of those bullying you.
それからいじめを放任した担任教師の名前を教えろ
And then the names of any
teachers who failed to stop them!
I'll make them all pay!
しかるべき報いを食らわしてやる
Sometimes, Nii-chan, you're hotter than fire.
兄ちゃんって 時折炎より熱いよね
I'm in love.
やっぱ惚れるよ
Oh, I get it... It's cosplay.
ああ分かった コスプレだ
Don't call a girl wearing a skirt cosplay!
女子がスカートを穿くのをコスプレとか言ってんじゃねえよ
Even I...
いくらあたしでも
get a little hurt.
ちょっと傷つくぞ
That's the kind of stuff that
そういうこと言われて あたしは小学生の頃死にたくなったっつーんだよ
made me want to kill myself in elementary school.
へ...ふーん お前にもデリケートな時代があったんだな
So, you were actually delicate at one time, huh?
If it isn't cosplay, and you aren't being bullied, what is it?
いじめでもコスプレでもねーんなら 何だよ
Well, I was wondering if it was cute...
いや ほら 可愛いかなーと思って
し...しかし 可愛いかなって言われても
I don't know whether I'd call it cute or not...
It's cute, isn't it?
可愛いだろ
I-It sure is...
か...可愛いな
K-Karen-chan...
か...火憐ちゃん
Thank you!
ありがとう 兄ちゃんが褒めてくれて 嬉しいな
I'm so happy you complimented me, Nii-chan!
I'm so happy. So happy... Yay!
嬉しいなったら嬉しいなっ わーいっ
I feel so relaxed when I'm hanging on to Nii-chan...
いや こうして兄ちゃんに抱きついてると落ち着くなあ
やっぱ包容力のある兄ちゃんは抱きつき具合が違うよな
It just feels so good, giving you a big hug like this!
テンピュール枕とか 多分こんな感じなんだろうな
This must be how a Tempur-Pedic pillow feels!
Stop it! It feels creepy.
やめろ 気持ち悪い 気持ち悪い気持ち悪い気持ち悪い
Creepy! Creepy! Creepy!
I'm sorry.
ごめん 本当本当本当に気持ち悪いから 離れてくれ
It really, really, really feels creepy.
Get away from me!
What is this?
なんなの 何の嫌がらせなの
What did I do to you?
Karen-chan, what is the meaning of all this?
火憐ちゃん そのキャラは一体どういうこと
何って言われても
I don't know how to answer that...
I know. From now on, I've decided
うん これからは兄ちゃんには絶対に逆らわない
to be a good little sister who loves her brother and would never disobey him.
兄貴ラブの妹というキャラで売っていくことにしたんだ
I don't want that!
売って来られても買わねえよ
And I think that character would overlap with Kanbaru!
あとそれ 神原とかとキャラ被るから
Kanbaru.
神原
Um... Karen-chan.
ああ えっとな火憐ちゃん
Kanbaru is my junior by one year.
神原っつーのは 僕の一個下の後輩でな
Yes...
そう 神原駿河
Kanbaru Suruga.
Huh?
あれあれ まだ僕フルネームは言ってねえよな
I didn't say her full name yet, did I?
Karen-chan.
火憐ちゃん
Nii-chan, I have a request!
兄ちゃん お願いがありまひゅ
Would you please introduce me to Kanbaru-sensei?
どうかこの愚妹めに神原先生を紹介してはいただけないでしょうか
Well, come to think of it,
まあ 考えて見りゃ 現代においては格闘技も一種のスポーツだもんな
martial arts is a type of sport, isn't it?
I guess it makes perfect sense that you'd know
お前が全国選手の 地元の星であるところの神原のことを知ってても
a local star and national-level player like Kanbaru.
全然不思議じゃねえわけか
Please, Nii-chan...
お願いします兄ちゃん いやさ お兄様
Nay, Onii-sama.
Don't say "nay."
いやさとか言うな
Aye, sir.
ほいさっ
That's a good answer, but...
いい返事だけどもな
I'm so honored that you'd step on me...
いっやあ 兄ちゃんに踏まれて光栄だなあ
And I'm seriously sick of seeing you bow.
つーかお前の土下座とか マジで見飽きてんだよ
何かあるたびごとに下座とかすんな
Don't bow every time something happens.
Just so you know,
言っとくけどな
土下座何て現代社会においては一種の暴力だからな
in modern society, bowing is a form of violence!
分かった じゃあ足舐める
Got it! I'll lick your feet, then.
親指から順番に舐めるから
I'll start with the big toe and work my way up!
That's why I'm telling you to stop!
だからそういうことをやめろっつってんだよ
Fine... Then I'll give you my virginity.
分かった じゃ処女やる
兄ちゃんにあたしの処女やるから
I'll give you my virginity, Nii-chan!
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
I don't want my little sister's virginity!
妹の処女なんざいるか
一応気にしといてやるけど 火憐ちゃん
I guess I should ask to be sure.
Karen-chan, you don't act like this outside, do you?
お前 外じゃそんなことしてねえだろうな
With your friends, classmates,
友達とか 同級生とか 学校の先生とか相手に
or teachers at school?
するわけねえじゃん あたし みんなの憧れなんだから
Of course not.
Everyone looks up to me.
Anyway, I'm amazed Tsukihi-chan loaned you those clothes.
しかし月火ちゃんの奴 よく服を貸してくれたな
You're gonna stretch the fabric wearing them.
お前が着たら布が伸びちゃうだろうに
That's why I took them quietly...
うん だからこっそり借りたんだ
She's gonna get mad at you later.
あとで怒られるぞ あいつの方が怖いんだから
She's scarier than you are.
I hate to say this after you complimented me,
兄ちゃんに褒めてもらっておいてなんだけど
but skirts don't seem to match my skin.
やっぱスカートってのはどうもあたしの肌に合わねえな
But this miniskirt works great for kicking.
とは言え このミニスカ 蹴り足出すにはいい感じだぜ
By the way, Karen-chan,
ちなみに火憐ちゃん お前どうやって僕が神原と仲良しだって知ったんだ
how did you learn I was friends with Kanbaru?
Oh, the unofficial Kanbaru-sensei fan club, Kanbaru Tool,
ああうん それは神原先生の非公式ファンクラブ
sent me a newsletter with lots of pictures of you in it.
「神原スール」が配布しているメルマガに添付されたスナップに
やけに兄ちゃんが見切れてたから
Kanbaru Tool
This is the unofficial fan club,
made by your host,
a huge Kanbaru Suruga fan.
It is unofficial.
There are no dues.
It's a place for comrades
who secretly love
Kanbaru Suruga to gather.
!! No trolling !!
She didn't know those pictures were taken, did she?
盗撮だよな それ
And then my own investigations revealed
それで調べてみれば
何と神原先生は兄ちゃんを師のように仰いでおられるとか
that she looks up to you like a teacher.
Well, that's true, I guess.
まあ 間違えっちゃいねえけど
I think this must be karma, Nii-chan.
これは何かの縁だと思うんだよ 兄ちゃん
お願いだから神原先生を紹介してくんないかな
Would you please introduce me to Kanbaru-sensei?
Karma, huh?
縁ね...
It may sound odd to say this,
自分で言うのもなんだけれど
きっと神原先生とあたしは 気が合うと思うんだよな
but I think Kanbaru-sensei and I would get along!
But I have no intention of
introducing my sister to Kanbaru.
だが僕は 神原に妹を紹介するつもりはないのだ
紹介できない理由がある
There's a reason I can't.
It's because I know her sexual proclivities,
それは 神原の一般的にはあまりに知られていない性癖を
僕は立場上知ってしまっているがゆえの理由である
which most people are unaware of.
Karen-chan.
火憐ちゃん
What is it, Nii-chan?
何だい 兄ちゃん
Give it up.
諦めろ
Now, let's talk, Nii-chan.
さあ兄ちゃん 話し合おう
You're telling me you won't do a favor for your adorable little sister?
可愛い妹の頼みが聞けねえってのかよ
I'm thinking otherwise.
だったらあたしにも考えがあるぞ
ど...土下座で駄目なら 迷わず暴力とか
I-If bowing doesn't work, you
immediately resort to violence?
No way...
ありえない
Seriously impossible!
ぶっちゃけありえない
Impossible?
ありえない じゃあどうしろっつーんだよ 兄ちゃん
Then what am I supposed to do, Nii-chan?
Is there any way to get through to you besides talking?
話し合い以外にあたしの念を通す方法があるってのか
We need to have a game...
なら 勝負しかねえか
If we fight, we have a game.
揉めたら勝負だろ 僕達の場合は
That's our rule.
言っとくけど 対等じゃねえぞ
And just so we're clear, it won't be fair.
I'm doing this to satisfy your request, not for myself.
今回はお前からの一方的な要求なんだからな 火憐ちゃん
Karen-chan, this game won't be fair.
ゲームで言うなら 子と子じゃなくて 親と子の勝負だ
I'll have a huge advantage.
Okay, that works.
へえ いいぜ それで行こう 兄ちゃんも分かってんじゃねえか
I guess you understand.
Sure, you can choose whatever rules you want.
ああ どんなルールでも好きに決めていいぞ
To meet Kanbaru-sensei,
あたしは神原先生に会うためになら
I'll pass any test!
どんな条件でもクリアする
Wait a second.
ちょっと待ってろ 道具を用意する
I'll get the tools ready.
お 兄ちゃん 早かったな
Nii-chan, that was fast.
Closed
ん 兄ちゃん その手にしているのは
Nii-chan?
That's my toothbrush you're holding, isn't it?
あたしの歯ブラシじゃないか
ま まさか 兄ちゃん
Y-You're not...
Nii-chan?
You're going to stick that toothbrush
その歯ブラシをあたしの尻に突き立てるつもりか
up my butt?!
That's my brother...
さすがはあたしの兄ちゃんだぜ 恐ろしいことを考えやがる
Terrifying!
No, your brother isn't planning anything that terrifying.
いや お前の兄ちゃんはそんな恐ろしいことは考えない
Karen-chan,
火憐ちゃん 歯ブラシってのは歯を磨くための道具なんだぜ
a toothbrush is for brushing teeth.
兄ちゃん 確かに歯ブラシは歯を磨くための道具かもしれねえが
Nii-chan,
you may be right, and a toothbrush may be for brushing teeth.
それがどうしたってんだ
But what of it?
別にここで歯を磨けって言うわけじゃねえだろ
You aren't going to tell me to brush my teeth here, are you?
No.
そう そんなことは言わない
No
No, I'm not.
磨けなんて言わない
I won't have you brush them.
I'm going to brush them.
磨くのは僕だ
And I'm not going to brush my teeth.
それも僕の歯を磨くんじゃねえぜ
お前の歯を 僕が磨くのだ
I'm going to brush your teeth.
Um, I don't understand.
いや わっけわかんねえんだけど
兄ちゃんがあたしの歯を磨いてくれるのか
You're going to brush my teeth?
それがどうして勝負になるんだ
How is that a game?
お前とか月火とか 美容室で髪切ったりするだろ
You and Tsukihi-chan get your hair cut at a beauty parlor, right?
だけど僕はああいうの結構抵抗があるんだよ
But I don't really like those.
知らない人間に頭触られるって 変に緊張するっていうか
I get nervous when someone I don't know
touches my head.
Yeah, I only want the stylists I know cutting mine.
あたしだって見知ってる美容師さん以外には切って欲しくねえよ
Psychologically, you have to be fairly close
心理学的にも 髪の毛を触るってのは
かなり親密な間柄じゃねえと許されないことらしくってな
to someone before you'll allow them to touch your hair.
女子とかにゃー身体触られるよりも
I've heard that some girls hate
髪の毛触られるほうが嫌だって奴もいるそうじゃないか
having their hair touched more than their bodies.
うん で それが
What of it?
It's called "touching."
タッチングって言ってな
まあ一番わかりやすいのが散髪って奴なんだけど
The most obvious example is hair-cutting.
そういう話のひとつが 歯磨きなのだ
Another example is tooth-brushing.
A moment ago, you didn't think it was a big deal.
お前はさっき気軽に捉えたようだが
But ordinarily, having someone else brush your teeth is unthinkable.
歯磨きを他人に任せるという経験は
通常ありえるものじゃない
普通は自分でできるし 自分でやるもんだからな
Normally, you can do it yourself, and usually, you do.
In other words, Karen-chan,
つまりだ 火憐ちゃん
他人に歯を磨かれる行為には
having someone else brush your teeth
かなりの心理的抵抗が生じるってことなんだ
causes major psychological resistance.
その心理的抵抗に五分間耐えることができたら
If you can withstand
that psychological resistance for five minutes, you win.
お前の勝ちということにしてやろう
If you do, I'll introduce you to Kanbaru.
そのときは神原を紹介してやる
If you cry uncle before the five minutes are up, I win.
五分以内に音を上げたら僕の勝ちだ
そのときは神原は紹介しない
And I won't introduce you...
なあんだ 兄ちゃんがあまりにも改まって言うから
Is that all?
You made such a big deal out of it,
さすがのあたしもちょっとビビっちまってたぜ
even I was starting to get a little scared.
I'm a bit disappointed.
ちょっとがっかりしたくらいだな
そうか
Are you?
Sure! It sounds great to me.
ああ むしろ望むところと言いたいくらいだ
そりゃ赤の他人に歯磨きされんのはヤダけどさ
I mean, I wouldn't want a total stranger doing it,
but you'll be doing it, right, Nii-chan?
この場合はやるのが兄ちゃんなわけじゃん
だったら別に平気だよ
Then I'll be fine.
はっきり言ってあたし
I'll clarify this.
兄ちゃんには何をされても恥ずかしくねえよ
No matter what you do to me, I won't be embarrassed.
僕が途中で音を上げたときはお前の勝ちってことでいいよ
If I give up before time expires, you win.
あの偉大なる神原先生を紹介してもらおうっていうのに
For an introduction to the great Kanbaru-sensei,
そんな楽勝じゃ
I think this is a bit too easy.
ちょっと申し訳ねえ気がするなあ
Actually, I'd hoped for something more challenging.
むしろもっと困難なハードルを設置して欲しかったのに
Okay, then we can start, right?
じゃ勝負開始でいいな
Sit down there.
そこ座れよ
Okay!
あーん
Say ahhh.
Ahhh.
あーん
Now, feel the terror
さあ その身をもって偉大なる神原先生の恐怖を味わうがいい
of the great Kanbaru-sensei for yourself.
Kanbaru-sensei's fetishistic ideas will cause your defeat.
神原先生のフェチ的アイデアで敗北するのだ
お前も本望だろう
You must be overjoyed.
Do you finally understand?
今頃気付いたか
しかし手遅れだぜ 火憐ちゃん
But it isn't too late, Karen-chan.
何せ 身体の外側ではなく
I'm not messing with the exterior of your body.
I'm messing with the interior.
身体の内側をいじるのだ
非常にわかりやすく言ってしまうと 快感が生じるのである
To simplify this,
it brings you pleasure.
Thin hairs are stimulating
肉体のデイケートな部分を細い毛先で撫で回すというのだから
delicate parts of your body,
それで気持ちよくないわけがないのだ
so it must feel good.
やるじゃないか こうなるとこっちもやる気になる
Not bad...
It makes me want to try harder.
If you give up now, Karen-chan, you'll feel good.
さっさと音を上げたほうが楽になれるぜ 火憐ちゃん
いや 楽じゃなくなれるぜ
Or rather you'll stop feeling good!
Oh, no...
やべえ 喘ぎ声にも似た火憐の声を聞いてると
Hearing her moan makes me feel really weird...
すげえ変な気持ちになる
It makes my heart race!
ドキドキする
00:03:24
00:03:23
00:03:21
00:03:20
00:03:17
00:03:16
00:03:14
00:03:13
00:03:10
Tsukihi
Phoenix
Chapter
Tsukihi
Phoenix
Part 1
ARAGO
She's really cute...
すげえ可愛い
This is seriously bad.
マジでやばいって 火憐ってこんな可愛かったっけ
Was Karen always this cute?
あれ あれあれ
Huh? Huh?
ひょっとしてだけど
This is just a possibility,
僕の妹って世界一可愛いんじゃねえ
but could my sister be the cutest girl in the world?
I've always thought the ideal
woman was Hanekawa Tsubasa,
今の今まで 僕は理想の女子っていうのは羽川翼のことだと思っていたけど
それはひょっとして認識ミスだったのか
but could I have been mistaken?
Even if she isn't better than Hanekawa,
羽川以上ってことはないにしても
それでもこいつは羽川といい勝負ができるんじゃ
she could really give her a good run for her money.
No, no, no... Wait!
いやいやいや 待て自分
何を言ってるんだ
What am I saying?
No human could match Hanekawa.
羽川と勝負できる人類なんかいるわけねえだろ
This is a hallucination!
錯覚だ錯覚
この特殊なシチュエーションが僕を酔わせているだけ
This special situation is weakening me. That's all!
わかってる そんなことわかってる
I know that! I know that!
B-But...
で でも
か 火憐ちゃん
K-Karen-chan...
Karen-chan...
火憐ちゃん 火憐ちゃん 火憐ちゃん
に 兄ひゃん
Nii-chan...
にいひゃん いいよ
It's okay.
何してはるんどすか
What are you doing?
Onii-han, Karen-han, please tell me what exactly is going on here?
お兄はん 火憐はん 何どすえ この状況
W-Wait, Tsukihi-chan!
ま 待て月火ちゃん 違うんだ
It's not what you think!
Why is my brother happily pushing Karen-chan
なんでお兄ちゃんが歯ァ磨いたりしたげながら
火憐ちゃんを慈愛顔でベッドに押し倒してるの
onto the bed while brushing her teeth?
なんで火憐ちゃんは私の服を着て
Why is Karen-chan wearing my clothes and
お兄ちゃんからうっとり顔でベッドに押し倒されてるの
smiling happily while being pushed onto the bed by my brother?
なんで僕  歯ァ磨いたりしたげながら
Why am I pushing my little sister onto
実の妹を慈愛顔でベッドに押し倒してるんだ
the bed with a smile while brushing her teeth?
なんであたし 実の妹の服を着て
Why am I wearing my little sister's clothes
実の兄からうっとり顔でベッドに押し倒されてるんだよお
smiling as my big brother pushes me onto the bed?
びっくりした
What a surprise!
た 助かったぜ月火ちゃん ありがとう
Y-You saved us, Tsukihi-chan!
Thank you!
Would the judge be merciful?
温情判決が下されるのか 情状酌量の余地ありか
Would there be room for
extenuating circumstances?
せめて執行猶予くらいはつくものかと
Let there at least be a stay of execution,
僕と火憐はにわかに期待した
Karen-chan and I hoped.
Would you two stay like that for a moment?
二人とも ちょっとそのままの姿勢で待っててくれるかな
I'm running to the convenience store to buy an awl.
すぐにコンビニ行って 千枚通しを買ってくるから
There would not be.
期待空振り 死刑判決だった
We were given the death penalty.
Tsukihi-chan, I don't think they sell awls at the convenience store.
月火ちゃん コンビニに千枚通しは売ってないと思うよ
専門の工具店とか行かなきゃ買えないって
You'd have to go to a specialty goods store!
Nii-chan, you're heavy.
兄ちゃん 重い
Oh, sorry.
ああ 悪い
Closed
So, Nii-chan, about our game...
で 兄ちゃん
勝負なんだけど
It's way past five minutes.
五分はとっくに経ってるぞ
Crap...
じゃ 仕方ねえか 約束は約束だしな
Fine... A promise is a promise.
オッケーオッケー 火憐ちゃん
Okay, Karen-chan.
神原のこと 紹介してやっよ
I'll introduce you to Kanbaru.
You did well, Karen-chan.
よく頑張ったな 火憐ちゃん お前の勝ちだよ
You win.
うん 今日のところは兄ちゃんの負けだ 認めといてやる
I lose this time.
I'll accept it.
に 兄ちゃん
N-Nii-chan?
What?
なんだよ
ま まあ もし兄ちゃんがどうしてもって言うんなら
I-If you really insist, and only because you insist,
仕方ないから三本勝負にしてあげてもいいんだぞ
we can go best two out of three.
You know, Tsukihi-chan interrupted us midway.
ほ ほら
途中で月火ちゃんの邪魔が入ったし
That normally means it's a tie.
普通ああいうときはノーゲームじゃん
A-And there's still time before Tsukihi-chan will get back...
そ それに 月火ちゃんが帰ってくるまで時間を持て余すし
We can go into extra innings if you'd like.
気散じに延長戦に付き合ってやってもいいんだぜ
えっと
Uh...
O-Okay, maybe I will...
じゃ じゃあ その再戦を申し込んじゃおっかな
Y-Yeah.
お おう 挑まれた以上 あたしは せ せ背中は見せない
Now that you've said that, I can't turn you down.
受けて 受けて起つぜ
I accept... I accept your challenge!
こ 今度は親と子 変えてやってみるとか
Th-This time, you want to do me?
Y-Yeah, th-that will be fair.
う うん そのほうがフェアだよね
そんなわけで 今朝を境に
And so, starting that morning, Karen and I
僕と火憐は少しだけ 仲良くなったのだった
began to get along a little better.
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
I'Mayoi!
We're the fire sisters!
Good evering to all you watching the preview!
Will you bear with me for a while,
knowing that I have Heaven's blessing in speaking out against the injustice that thrives in the world?
Meanie!
What!
Let's talk about rock-paper-scissors today.
Rock-paper-scissors is omnipresent in our daily lives, but there is more.
Don't you think that, when grown-ups play it and not children like me,
I've got a new hairstyle!
what they call the various moves is rather befit of kindergarten?
Rock, paper, scissors.
Isn't that a rather immature thing to say in a game?
Now my only secret is...
Uh...
This must not stand, for we are dealing not with a game, but with a contest!
Hence, yours truly proposes with great conviction that these terms be changed to appear more adult.
Shaggy Hair!
What!
Running scissors.
A rock between a hard place.
And lastly, origami paper!
Now the competitive aspect is gone, to say nothing of the playful part.
Next time! Tsukihi Phoenix, Part 2!
Next Time
Tsukihi Phoenix Part 2
Mayoi sure you watch it!
Truth is,
I'm growing it out.
What